Richard Scarry Papers 1997.0048
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series III: Ephemera, 1989-1997
  - Artwork for Picturebook Corner (1 pc.), undated (Box 1:, Folder 53)
  - Busiest People Ever, Peaceable Kingdom Press poster, 1987 (Box OS:, Folder 1309)
  - The Busy, Busy World of Richard Scarry by Walter Retan and Ole Risom, 1997
    - Original color artwork (back cover), ca. 1997 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
  - "Little Richard Totem Pole Book" (by Patsy Scarry?), undated (Box OS:, Folder 1308)
  - Puzzles (catalog page), ca. 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 55)
  - Scarry character dolls
    - Hilda Hippo, undated (Box 4:, Folder 76)
    - Lowly Worm in apple car, undated (Box 4:, Folder 77)
    - Motorcycle, undated (Box 4:, Folder 78)
      This toy is meant to go with the Sergeant Murphy doll in 4:80.
    - Pig (Mr. Frumble?), undated (Box 4:, Folder 79)
    - Sergeant Murphy, undated (Box 4:, Folder 80)
    - Lowly Worm and Huckle Cat, ca. 1995 (Box 5:)
  - Scarry character dolls, design sketches, undated (Box 1:, Folder 56)
  - Stickers, autographed, undated (Box 1:, Folder 57)
- Series IV: Personal Papers, 1946-1989
  - Army separation qualification record, Scarry, Richard, 1946 March 24 (Box 1:, Folder 58)
  - Autobiographical notes (typescripts and manuscripts), 1986, 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 59)
  - Autobiographical sketches by Scarry (typescript copies), undated (Box 1:, Folder 60)
  - Biographical material, published, undated (Box 1:, Folder 61)
  - Biographical material, unidentified authors, undated (Box 1:, Folder 62)
  - Biographical sketch by Patricia Scarry (typescript and copies), undated (Box 1:, Folder 63)
  - Card game, ca. 1961 (Box 4:, Folder 75)
  - Clippings: Scarry in Switzerland, 1969-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 64)
  - Emergency contact and financial information, undated (Box 1:, Folder 65)
  - Golden Book royalty list, ca. 1971? (Box 1:, Folder 66)
  - Handkerchief set, ca. 1963 (Box 4:, Folder 73)
  - Little Bear and the Four Seasons by Patricia Scarry (typescript), undated (Box 1:, Folder 67)
  - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 68)
  - Receipts, 1989 November (Box 1:, Folder 69)
  - Rubber stamps (airmail), undated (Box 4:, Folder 72)
  - Rubber stamp (fly), undated (Box 4:, Folder 74)
  - Sales figures, 1986 December, 1987 March (Box 1:, Folder 70)
- Series V: Audiovisual materials, 19-- -1997
  - Audiocassettes
    - Dick Scarry: Gstaad [last word unclear] Interview with the children's author discussing his life including his military service during the Second World War, his relationships with publishers, and his philosophy of writing books to appeal to adults as well as children. His wife, Patricia, is also interviewed, [19--] (Other Audio 870)
    - Huck's tape: [Interview with Huck Scarry] Interview with the children's author and illustrator, Richard Scarry, Jr. ("Huck"), who talks about his childhood in Connecticut and Switzerland with his father, Richard Scarry, [19--] (Other Audio 871)
    - Patsy's tape: [Interview with Patsy Scarry] Interview with the children's author, Patsy Scarry, who talks about her husband, Richard Scarry, [1996?] (Other Audio 872)
    - "Mae West", undated (Cassette 1997-0048/AC1)
  - Video cassettes
    - James Marshall in his studio [S.l.]: Houghton Mifflin. Visit with Marshall where he talks about his experiences as an author and illustrator and demonstrates his drawing and painting technique, circa 1987 (Other Video 115)
    - Sendak [videorecording] / Weston Woods Studios, Inc.; producer, Morton Schindel; screenwriter, Maurice Sendak, Weston, CT: Weston Woods Studios. Author and illustrator Maurice Sendak discusses significant events in his life and the impact that they have had on his works, circa 1986 (Other Video 116)